♪♪
Well, looks like one of the
boys got up earlier than we did.
Hey, Sheriff, any
sign of the body?
Nope, probably
never will find it.
That boat was
blown to smithereens.
Any idea what
caused the explosion?
Your guess is as good as mine.
Get some backup down there.
That's odd.
What's that?
This engine's stone cold.
Sherry didn't want me to come
up last night, because she said
she couldn't get the
negatives till this morning.
But if she went somewhere
before we got here,
she didn't drive.
Maybe she used a boat.
Could be.
He works down at
the end of the road...
Yeah.
Southeast Security Bank.
Two days ago.
Come on, guys. We
have a serious problem.
I want to hear some solutions.
Well, is this my lucky day!
I'd hoped to catch one of
you, and here you all are.
I, uh, I hope... I hope
I'm not interrupting.
What is it this time?
Well, I got an idea why Eric
Gaston was killed, and I...
I wanted to run it by you
since you were all
such good friends.
Mr. Matlock, Eric was killed
because your client
owed him $25,000.
No, he wasn't.
He was murdered because
he was blackmailing you.
All of you.
No, k-keep going.
D-Don't lower your
pulse rate on my account.
He wasn't blackmailing us.
Oh, yes, he was.
And then when he died, Sherry
Brown started blackmailing you.
That's why she was
killed this morning.
Sherry Brown is dead?
I don't believe that.
You seem surprised.
As if you hadn't
tried to kill her before.
At fir... at first,
I thought you
were trying to kill
me, but then when I
realized it was her, I thought
you were after Eric's ledger.
Wrong again.
It was the negatives.
That's what you were after.
What the hell is he talking
about? You have any idea
- what he's talking about?
- I got no idea.
- Not me.
- Well...
those negatives will
surface pretty soon.
In the meantime, uh...
I wouldn't go anywhere
for the next week or two,
except to, uh, to court.
I'll see you there.
You find out
anything at the bank?
Now, don't I always
find out something?
- No, not always.
- Most of the time, though.
Well, a lot of the time.
At least 75% of the t... Conrad!
Two days ago, Sherry Brown
cleaned out all of
her bank accounts.
Withdrew every last cent.
Well, that probably explains
why they've still found no trace
of her body out at Wheeler Lake.
And why all the boys
went slack-jawed
when I told them she was dead.
Weren't bluffing, were they?
No.
Looks like she
faked her own death
so she could skip town
and nobody would follow her.
Think she took the
negatives with her?
Might have.
Well, they might
still be in there.
Well, they might be, yeah.
Why don't I take a look around?
You gonna break and enter?
The window was already
broke the other day, remember?
Ah.
Well, that's strange.
Hey, mister?
- Uh...
- Yeah?
Uh... aren't you gonna leave
anything for Ms., uh, Brown?
Oh, no, she's having
all her mail forwarded.
- Forwarded?
- Yeah.
T-To where?
They don't tell me that.
Oh, they-they...
Ben... Hey, you get something?
Now, don't I always
find something?
Conrad!
She had her mail forwarded
to 9070 Lakeshore Drive.
Lakeshore Drive?
I never heard of it.
Lakeshore Drive.
That's in Chicago.
♪ Whoo, whoo... ♪
♪ Come on, baby,
if you wanna go ♪
♪ Gonna hop on
that train to Chicago ♪
♪ Come on, baby,
if you wanna go ♪
♪ Gonna hop on
that train to Chicago ♪
♪ Whoo, whoo... ♪
♪ It may rain all
day or rain all night ♪
♪ In Chicago,
gonna be all right ♪
♪ Come on, baby,
if you wanna go ♪
♪ Gonna hop on
that train to Chicago ♪
♪ Whoo, whoo ♪
♪ Whoo! ♪
♪ Whoo, whoo... ♪
♪ Fee, fi, and a fo, fum ♪
♪ Show me, baby,
that you wanna come ♪
♪ Come on, baby,
if you wanna go ♪
♪ Gonna hop on
that train to Chicago ♪
♪ Whoo, whoo... yeah! ♪
Oh, geez, hey, I am so sorry.
I don't know what I
was thinking about.
- Hey, are you okay?
- Yeah, just hold it.
- Okay, um, look. Give me your name and...
- Yeah, we're fine.
Your-your phone number, and
let me call my insurance agent.
- No, that's not necessary.
- No, no.
Please, I insist. Look, you may
feel fine now, but you get home,
your neck could be sore,
your alignment could be off.
All right, all right,
it's Henry Macklin.
- Hey, nice to meet you, Henry.
- Yeah.
I mean, not like
this or anything.
- Yeah, I know.
- Right, yeah. Oh...
My name's Henry, M-A-C
- K-L-I-N.
- M-A-C-K-L-I-N.
- Yes?
- How you doing?
I'm Conrad McMasters.
Henry Macklin is
a friend of mine.
I've known him
and Gloria for years.
Is that so?
Well, anyway, I
just got into town.
He suggested I come by.
He said his friends
are my friends.
They sure are. Come on in.
Blackjack, all right.
Enjoy it.
Okay...
Three cards.
Uh... My bet... Three hundred.
See your 300, raise you 300.
I'll just call.
What do you got?
Three 10's.
Two pair.
Huh.
Yeah?
Mr. Davis wants
to buy you a drink.
Mr. Davis?
Yes, Mr. Davis.
Oh, right, Mr. Davis.
Where is he?
Follow me.
How much is there?
Come in.
Mr. McMasters, nice to meet you.
- How you doing?
- Don Davis.
Thank you.
I try and meet all
my new guests.
I hear you're from out of town.
Yeah.
But you have friends here?
Oh, yeah, I did some business
with Henry Macklin
a couple of years ago.
And so he and I have
been friends ever since.
How about a drink?
Another, uh, oh,
soda water and lemon,
- or you want something harder?
- No.
No, I'm fine, thank you.
You're very
observant, Mr. Davis.
You're on quite a roll.
Yeah.
So, does that mean
it's gonna end?
I never cut winners off.
- Never.
- Oh... sure you do, Mr. Davis.
The easy way.
What do you mean?
You got a deck of cards?
I beg your pardon?
Do you have a deck of cards?
Five-card draw?
Two queens.
Right?
Yeah.
Which beats the hell
out of my two fives.
You know my roll is gonna end
as soon as you tell that dealer
down there to make it end.
You're good.
Very good.
I'm also available.
Why don't you come
back Saturday night?
I'll let you deal
some blackjack.
If your work is as
good as it looks,
we'll talk about your cut.
And your future.
Okay.
♪ This boy was born good luck ♪
♪ This you will see ♪
♪ Got $700 ♪
♪ So don't you mess with me ♪
♪ You know I'm him ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Everybody knows I'm him ♪
♪ I'm him, yes, I'm him ♪
♪ Well, I'm your
hoochie coochie man ♪
♪ The whole wide
world knows I'm him ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Hoochie coochie man. ♪
Yeah, baby... we're gonna
burn them tonight, guys.
- That was good, man...
- That's it, man, we're ready.
Yeah!
- Yo, man, this dude is crazy!
- Whoo!
I tell ya... Hot
rehearsals, hot, hot.
Oh, man, see y'all tonight, man.
We'll see you, man.
Them horns was special.
- Very special, very...
- Right.
- Gary, take care of 'em, man.
- All right, buddy.
- Tony!
- Yeah?
Yo, man, don't break the
strings on the stage tonight, okay?
Don't worry, bro.
Everything is cool.
- Yeah, don't worry. Right.
- Don't worry about it.
- Take care of him, guys.
- All right.
Drive safe.
- Bring him in! Get him in here!
- Come on!
Get him!
You owe me, Ty.
Oh, Frankie, man.
Look, I'll pay you
tomorrow, I swear.
That's great, buddy.
But, this time, I don't
want you to forget.
Give him something to remember.
Oh, Frank...!
Ben.
Ty.
What happened?
Frankie Lance.
- You've been gambling.
- No.
You promised you
wouldn't gamble.
Here. Call somebody from
Gamblers Anonymous right now!
Ben, I don't... No
more lies, no excuses!
Call!
Y-You're whipped,
and you know it.
Yeah, I know.
Well, call!
I already have.
You did?
I did.
You don't have a good
track record, you know.
Are you gonna stay with it?
I promise.
Are you sure?
I'll lay you eight to five.
Hello, Sherry.
Looking pretty fine
for a dead woman.
Some mail came for you.
What is he doing here?
Name's McMasters.
- He's a new dealer.
- No, he's a private investigator.
Hey!
All right, hey!
You don't have to get ugly.
I just came to find Sherry.
Now that I found
her, I'll just leave.
- Sit down!
- Hey!
And head straight
for the police.
I got no reason to do that.
You lie a lot, you
know that, Conrad?
Hey, if you're so worried
about the cops, you should do
something about her, not me.
What does that mean?
It means, as soon
as the police in Atlanta
find out she cleared
out her bank account,
they're gonna be
on your doorstep.
Or didn't she tell you?
He's out of his mind.
Tell me what?
Tell you that
Sherry's gotten herself into
so much trouble in Atlanta
that she faked her own
death to get everybody...
Including the
police... Off her back.
Is that true?
No.
Hey, lightning's
gonna strike you.
- Shut up!
- I said I'd help you
because Eric and
I were old friends.
- Now, did you lie to me, honey?
- No.
No.
He's lying.
Kick him out of here, Don.
Yeah, well, one of you is lying.
And being around liars
makes me uncomfortable!
Thanks a lot. Now I
have no place to go.
I'm just trying to find
out who killed Eric.
Yeah, well, I didn't, so why
don't you just leave me alone?
Sherry! You're the only
one that can help me.
♪♪
Sherry.
Look, look... the
murderer's got to be one of
the three guys you've
been blackmailing.
- Aren't you the genius!
- Hey!
You are playing a
very dangerous game.
No more. Game's over.
I've gone into retirement.
Think! Think.
They're not gonna
let you off the hook
until they get the
negatives and you're dead.
I'm telling the truth.
They're gonna find
you, just like I did.
And when they do, they're
gonna take their time killing you.
The negatives are in
a locker in the airport.
"C" Concourse.
What... the negatives...
What are they of?
You'll figure it out.
Oh, my God!
Call the police.
Please, nobody go outside.
What happened?
Somebody jumped.
I probably led
them right to her.
I should've just walked
her to her room, huh?
Oh, she knew what she was into.
She knew it got Eric killed.
That didn't stop her.
You couldn't have done anything.
But I was right there.
So was the killer.
He ought to be
feeling bad, not you.
Let's see here, now.
Hmm.
All right.
John Delaney, Tom Hermanski,
Roy Stevens... three suspects.
- Little younger, though.
- Yeah.
Judging from the car, I'd
say about 15 years younger.
Wouldn't you?
Yeah, that would
put them in college.
Yeah.
What do they got in
their hands, paintings?
Looks like it. What
would a bunch of jocks
want with a bunch of paintings?
I don't know.
You don't suppose they paid
Eric Gaston all that money
just to keep, you know,
that a secret, do you?
You know, if memory serves me,
I would say this is
the... untitled Braque.
And I would say this one is
the early Picasso.
They're valuable?
Well... that depends.
On what?
On how well the buyer
of the stolen paintings
took care of them.
I knew it.
Okay, when were they
stolen and where from?
The Metropolitan
Gallery in Atlanta.
About 15 years ago.
Unless I'm mistaken.
But then, you see, I rarely am.
Right, right.
Were the thieves caught?
No.
But something else
happened that night.
What happened?
A security guard
was shot and killed.
This meant it wasn't
only a burglary;
it was murder.
Now we know why Eric
Gaston was able to blackmail
those three guys for so long.
Yeah.
Murder, that makes a difference.
If it'd been just
simple robbery,
those negatives
would be worthless.
Why?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
- Statute of limitations.
- Yeah.
Run out a long time ago.
Wonder which one of
them pulled the trigger.
Well, they could
have hired somebody.
Oh, I don't think so.
It feels like one of
them, don't you think?
Yeah, yeah.
Why an art gallery?
Yeah, why not a bank
or a sporting goods
store or a liquor store?
Yeah. Three football
players robbing an art gallery.
Strange, isn't it?
Art majors?
Are you kidding?
Hasn't been an art major
on a Baxter University
football team since 1968.
George Stolberg.
Yeah, he thought it was going
to help him avoid the draft.
Well, maybe one of
them was an art minor.
No, not a chance.
Not those three.
The closest they ever got to art
was the Sunday morning funnies.
What about part-time jobs?
Well, Stevens, uh,
worked the radio station,
and it, uh, seems to me that,
uh, Delaney worked tables
at one of the sorority houses.
Tom Hermanski?
Tom, yeah, he, uh...
made a career out
of dating rich girls.
You know, I think
one of those guys
used to go with an art major.
Yeah, her daddy owned
an art gallery or something.
Big mucky-muck at some museum.
Who dated her? You remember?
Well, now let me
think about that.
♪ It's time to make a change ♪
♪ Time to pick myself up ♪
♪ Get up off the floor ♪
♪ 'Cause I've been there, baby ♪
♪ I've felt all the pain I can ♪
♪ No more till the blues
come back knocking ♪
♪ At my door ♪
♪ Mm, mm, mm... ♪
♪ My door. ♪
How's it going, Ben?
Pretty good, Ty. How about you?
So far, okay.
Have you any idea
what we're looking for?
Anything that'll tell us
who killed Eric Gaston.
You know, none of our suspects
are in any of these
team pictures.
Well, they didn't make the
team till Eric was a senior.
Remember, that was
the year he got expelled.
He must not have ordered
a picture, then, that year.
Well, he probably
wasn't in any of them.
He only played half a year.
I bet you that made him mad,
getting kicked out like that.
Not being able to enjoy
all that stuff that goes along
with being in a
championship team.
What?
Well, Mr. Delaney,
how's business?
Just fine.
Your secretary, Mrs. Harrison,
showed me your client list
for each of the last five years,
and, uh, you know,
it's getting smaller.
Well, it's only because
my clients' salaries
keep getting bigger.
Yeah.
Yeah, and-and-and she told me
that you recently
sold your house
and moved into an apartment
and that you sold your
Porsche that you used to drive
and that you did
have two secretaries,
but about a month ago
you let the other one go.
That sounds like considerable
belt-tightening to me.
Well, I prefer to
call it "streamlining."
Yeah.
The last thing you
needed was for Eric Gaston
to blackmail you for
more money, wasn't it?
Never been
blackmailed, Mr. Matlock.
Not by Eric, not by anybody.
Are you going to deny that
that's you in that picture?
All I know is, I couldn't
possibly have taken part
in that art theft.
Why not?
Well, I did a little
checking, Mr. Matlock.
Seems to me that
robbery took place
late on a Saturday afternoon
in November, is that right?
That's right. It was...
Let's see now, hold it...
It was November 11, 1975,
between 2:30 and 3:00.
Sorry. Couldn't
have been involved.
Why?
Well, I was doing
the same thing I did
every other Saturday afternoon
back then... playing football
in front of several thousand
Baxter University fans.
Nice try, but no cigar.
You remember, uh, um,
yeah, Martin Kravetz...
Remember him?
Trainer over there at Baxter.
Biggest football
fan I've ever seen.
You ask him the score
of any Baxter game,
and no... no matter how
long ago, he'll give it to you.
And if he's not sure,
he'll get out his scrapbook
of newspaper
clippings and look it up.
See?
You played football
that afternoon,
but only nine minutes
of the first quarter,
when you and Roy Stevens
were ejected for fighting.
That means you had to
leave the field, didn't you?
And, interestingly enough,
Tom Hermanski hit the showers
with some kind
of shoulder injury.
Now, the Metropolitan Art Museum
is only a ten-minute
drive from the stadium.
You could have gone over
there, used the information
that Tom Hermanski
got from his girlfriend,
helped yourself to a
couple of paintings,
put them in the trunk of the
car and been back to the stadium
by halftime, with
no one the wiser.
And that's exactly
what happened, isn't it?
Of course not.
That's ridiculous.
How did Eric get onto you?
Did-Did he hear you whispering
in the locker room about your...
your plans as to
this famous scam?
I did not steal any paintings,
and Eric was not
blackmailing me.
Okay.
Where were you
between 9:30 and 10:30
the morning Eric was killed?
I was in my office.
I got there at 9:00.
I didn't leave till
almost 7:00 that night.
Can anybody verify that?
Absolutely... my secretary.
No.
No, she was running an
errand for you. Remember?
You called her at her house
at 7:00 that morning
and asked her
to go to a box office, get you
some baseball tickets. Remember?
Oh, I do remember that.
Yeah, she didn't get in till
- almost 10:00.
- 11:00.
And that would have
given you plenty of time
to return to the office
after you'd killed Eric Gaston.
That's not true.
I was in my office that morning,
and you can't prove otherwise.
Oh, I'm afraid I can.
You remember that
big coffee stain on, uh...
the chair in your office?
Well, your secretary
had arranged
with Gold's Cleaning
Service to come over at 9:30
that morning and steam it out.
I guess she forgot to mention
it to you when you called her
at home, 'cause it was so early.
Anyway, when Mr. Gold
got there at 9:35,
he couldn't get in.
Nobody was there.
The lights were out.
The doors were locked.
Here's his invoice,
two days later.
See?
Says, "Unable to render services
at 9:30 a.m. Tuesday the 17th"
because of... "no one was
at the office" to let him in.
Well, he charged
you $30, anyway.
Highway robbery.
Well, now, we know
you were not at...
at your office at the
time of the murder.
You care to tell us
where you were?
No?
Well...
This ring was found on
Eric's finger by the police
when they arrived at the scene.
You recognize it?
No.
You don't?
Well, rings like this were
given to all the Baxter players
in 1975, the year you
won the championship.
See? It says so right there.
I don't know... it's kind of hard
to recognize without the stone.
Yeah, the ring is a mess.
The police think that
maybe... that maybe, uh,
Eric struggled with his
killer, and just before he died,
hit him so hard that
he crushed the stone.
But I have a couple
of problems with that.
I have a couple of problems.
The coroner found
a long, jagged cut
along Eric's left jaw.
And his report
said it was inflicted
just moments before his death.
And that would suggest that Eric
was the one that got
hit, rather than vice versa.
And the other thing is,
Eric didn't have a ring.
Of course he did. He
was a star running back.
- Remember?
- No, no, no, no.
That was the year he
was expelled for gambling.
Remember?
He only played a half season.
He didn't get a ring.
Look at this picture.
Now, this picture was
taken at, uh... at Eric's club
the night before he was killed.
Now, look here.
All of them have rings.
See, they all... all have rings.
But-But Eric... no ring.
See, no ring.
No ring.
What's...
what's happened to
your ring, Mr. Delaney?
I, uh... lost it recently.
Yeah?
Are you sure this
isn't your ring?
You sure you didn't
struggle with Eric
just before you shot him
and hit him so hard that
you crushed the stone
in his ring into
hundreds of pieces?
You knew my client
would be walking
through the door any minute.
You sure you
didn't take that ring
off your finger and
put it on Eric's finger
so everybody would believe
it was his instead of yours?
Look, you can twist
things all you want,
but that is not my ring.
Conrad?
You recognize her?
I don't know.
That's Robin Martel,
the girl you went
with in college.
The girl who wore
your ring for two years.
She'll testify
that she had it cut down
so it would fit her finger.
And when you took it
back two years later,
you had to wear it
on your pinky finger,
because it was too
big for the other fingers.
In other words, she will testify
that this is, indeed, your ring.
And when she does that,
I'm going to enter
it into evidence.
And when I do that,
two things will happen:
We will have proven
beyond a reasonable doubt
that my client over there
did not commit this crime;
and we're going to make
you look awfully suspicious,
not only for what happened
to Eric, but for what happened
to his girlfriend, Sherry
Brown, in Chicago.
And later on down the line,
what happened to that guard
during the art theft.
Mr. Delaney, you
remember once, you told me
"Gambling is for losers."
And it is.
And it seems... it seems
almost trite to say now
that murder is always
a gamble, and...
you took it and... and-and lost.
Ladies and
gentlemen of the jury,
have you reached a verdict?
We find the defendant,
Tyler Mullins,
not guilty. -
Thank you, ladies and
gentlemen of the jury.
This court is adjourned.
- Well...
- Thank you, Ben.
Thank you, Conrad.
I'm speechless, man.
All I can say is... ♪
Let's have some fun ♪
♪ You only live but once ♪
♪ And when you're
dead, it's done ♪
♪ So let the good
times roll, yeah ♪
♪ Oh, let the good
♪ We don't care if
you're young or old ♪
♪ Let's get together and
let the good times roll ♪
♪ Hey, there, bartender ♪
♪ Lock all the doors ♪
♪ If the police come around ♪
♪ Tell them the
joint is closed ♪
♪ But let the good
times roll, yeah ♪
♪ Oh, let the good
♪ We don't care if
you're young or old ♪
♪ Let's get together and
let the good times roll... ♪
Are you expecting somebody?
Yeah.
Friend of mine.
Hey, remember
Gamblers Anonymous?
I asked him to come
down here and maybe...
spend a little time with Ty.
♪ We don't care if you're
young or old, let's get together ♪
- ♪ And let the good times roll ♪
- He's also a record producer.
- New York.
- ♪ Well, let the good times roll... ♪
I sent him an airplane ticket.
Told him to come down
here and give Ty a listen.
With any luck, he might
wind up with a record contract.
♪ Oh, let the good times roll ♪
That's really nice of you, Ben.
- I'm a nice man.
- ♪ We don't care if you're ♪
♪ Young or old,
let's get together ♪
♪ And let the good times ♪
♪ Roll, roll,
roll, roll, yeah. ♪
You figured that's the only
way you'd ever get paid, huh?
That, too.
www.tvsubtitles.net